# Dawit Mureja Argaw

Ph.D. Candidate, EE, KAIST

## RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interests lie in the general areas of computer vision and deep learning with a particular focus on video-related topics including video restoration, video synthesis, video editing, long-form and multimodal video understanding, video summarization, and video generation but not limited to.

Webpage: https://dawitmureja.github.io

Email: dawitmureja@kaist.ac.kr

### **EDUCATION**

• KAIST

Integrated M.S./Ph.D. in Electrical Engineering

Daejeon, South Korea

Sep 2018 - Sep 2024 (expected)

KAIST

B.S. in Electrical Engineering; GPA: 3.9/4.3 (Magna Cum Laude)

Sep 2014 - Jul 2018

## RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

**NVIDIA** Research Santa Clara, CA Research Intern, Deep Imagination Research Group Nov 2023 - Present Adobe Research San Jose, CA Research Intern, Natural Language Group May 2023 - Sep 2023 **KAUST** Saudi Arabia (Remote) Research Intern, Image and Video Understanding (IVUL) Lab Nov 2022 - May 2023 Adobe Research San Jose, CA (Remote) Research Intern, Deep Learning Group Aug 2021 - Nov 2021 KAIST Daejeon, South Korea Research Assistant, Robotics and Computer Vision (RCV) Lab Sep 2018 - Sep 2023 Daejeon, South Korea Research Assistant, Multimodal AI (MMAI) Lab Sep 2023 - Present

#### Publications

- Scaling Up Video Summarization Pretraining with Large Language Models. CVPR, 2024.
   Dawit Mureja Argaw, Seunghyun Yoon, Fabian Caba Heilbron, Hanieh Deilamsalehy, Trung Bui, Zhaowen Wang, Franck Dernoncourt, Joon Son Chung.
- Towards Automated Movie Trailer Generation. CVPR, 2024.
   Dawit Mureja Argaw, Mattia Soldan, Alejandro Pardo, Chen Zhao, Fabian Caba Heilbron, In So Kweon, Bernard Ghanem.
- Long-range Multimodal Pretraining for Movie Understanding. ICCV, 2023.
   Dawit Mureja Argaw, Fabian Caba Heilbron, Joon-Young Lee, Markus Woodson, In So Kweon.
- The Anatomy of Video Editing: A Dataset and Benchmark Suite for AI-Assisted Video Editing. ECCV, 2022. Dawit Mureja Argaw, Fabian Caba Heilbron, Joon-Young Lee, Markus Woodson, In So Kweon.
- Long-term Video Frame Interpolation via Feature Propagation. CVPR, 2022. Dawit Mureja Argaw, In So Kweon.
- Motion-blurred Video Interpolation and Extrapolation. AAAI, 2021.
   Dawit Mureja Argaw, Junsik Kim, Francois Rameau, In So Kweon.
- Optical Flow Estimation from a Single Motion-blurred Image. AAAI, 2021.
   Dawit Mureja Argaw, Junsik Kim, Francois Rameau, Jae Won Cho, In So Kweon.
- Blurry Video Compression: A Trade-off between Visual Enhancement and Data Compression. WACV, 2024. Dawit Mureja Argaw, Junsik Kim, In So Kweon.
- Restoration of Video Frames from a Single Blurred Image with Motion Understanding. CVPR-W (Oral), 2021. Dawit Mureja Argaw, Junsik Kim, Francois Rameau, Chaoning Zhang, In So Kweon.

- Empirical study on using Adapters for debiased Visual Question Answering. CVIU, 2023. Jae Won Cho, Dawit Mureja Argaw, Yeongtaek Oh, Dong-Jin Kim, In So Kweon.
- LEMMS: Label Estimation of Multi-feature Movie Segments. ICCV-W, 2023. Bartolomeo Vacchetti, Dawit Mureja Argaw, Tania Cequtelli.
- ResNet or DenseNet: Introducing Shortcuts to ResNet. WACV, 2021. Chaoning Zhang\*, Philipp Benz\*, Dawit Mureja Argaw, Seokju Lee, Junsik Kim, Francois Rameau, Jean Charles Bazin, In So Kweon.
- DeePTZ: Deep Self-Calibration for PTZ cameras. WACV, 2020. Chaoning Zhang, Francois Rameau, Junsik Kim, Dawit Mureja Argaw, Jean Charles Bazin, In So Kweon.
- Revisiting Residual Networks with Nonlinear Shortcuts. BMVC (Spotlight), 2019.
   Chaoning Zhang, Francois Rameau, Seokju Lee, Junsik Kim, Philipp Benz, Dawit Mureja Argaw, Jean Charles Bazin, In So Kweon.
- Automatic spine segmentation from CT images using convolutional neural network via redundant generation of class labels. JCDE, 2019.
   Malinda Vania\*, Dawit Mureja Argaw\*, Deukhee Lee (\*equal contribution).

#### HONORS AND AWARDS

| HONORS AND AWARDS                                                                  |              |
|------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|--------------|
| • Top Reviewer Award Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS) | 2023         |
| Outstanding Reviewer Award CVEU Workshop at ICCV                                   | 2023         |
| Outstanding Reviewer Award International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)      | 2023         |
| • Best Poster Award What is Motion For? (WiMF) Workshop at ECCV                    | 2022         |
| Outstanding Reviewer Award European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV)           | 2022         |
| Finalist Qualcomm Innovation Fellowship Korea                                      | 2021         |
| Magna Cum Laude  KAIST Electrical Engineering Department                           | 2018         |
| • Excellent Research Award KAIST Undergraduate Research Participation (URP)        | 2017         |
| • Dean's List  KAIST School of Freshman                                            | 2015         |
| • KAIST Scholarship Full scholarship for B.S., and Integrated M.S./Ph.D. programs  | 2014-Present |

#### ACADEMIC SERVICES

- Reviewer: ICML, ICLR, NeurIPS, CVPR, ICCV, ECCV, BMVC, WACV, TPAMI, ICRA
- Student Volunteer: ICLR 2020, ICML 2020, NeurIPS 2020